# M.G. HACHEM

mgh@mghachem.com

### **ABOUT**

I design experiences for both the digital and the physical world. I create designs that emphasize ease of use and accessibility, and provide valuable solutions to end-users problems.

I believe good design is innovative, functional, clean, and honest.

## SKILLS

#### **LANGUAGES**

English (Fluent, first language) Arabic (Native) Spanish (B1-B2 level) Turkish (A2 level)

#### **CRAFT**

User needs research . Ideation . Sketching . Concept development . Illustration . Design research . Usercentered design . Human factors . Wireframing . Prototyping . Digital modelling . User Testing .

#### **SOFTWARE**

Balsamiq . Adobe XD . Invision . Illustrator . InDesign . Photoshop . Rhinoceros . AutoCAD . V-Ray rendering . Unity3D .

#### PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

HTML . CSS . Javascript . Python . C#

## **EDUCATION**

#### AMERICAN UNIVERSITY OF SHARJAH (SHARJAH, UAE)

Bachelor's of Architecture • N.A.A.B Accredited • 2014 Completed 178 credits split between architecture, visual, and product design.

#### UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA - DARDEN SCHOOL OF BUSINESS

Digital Product Management Specialisation • 2020

#### UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA, IRVINE

Project Management Principles and Practices Specialisation . 2020

#### UNIVERSITY OF MICHIGAN

User Experience Research and Design Specialisation • 2020

## WORK EXPERIENCE

#### TINKERLIST.TV (LEUVEN, BELGIUM, REMOTE)

Senior User Experience Designer . 2021 - Present

Conducted user research and interviews regularly to keep users at the forefront of the design process and leverage their knowledge and expertise.

Worked with the product team to overhaul the platform's flows, systems, interaction, and UI to align with user needs and expectations.

Collaborated with the CEO as part of a team responsible for research, design, and development of automation software that democratizes live production.

Opened the platform to new markets by adding RTL language support.

#### **ECOMZ** (BEIRUT, LEBANON)

Senior Customer and User Experience Designer . 2020 - 2021

Project and UX lead on a zero-code website builder project that enables users to create highly customizable SEO-ready e-commerce sites with little effort.

UX lead on a platform-wide revamp focused on improving usability, and accessibility.

Designed and developed the company's website and the ZenDesk helpdesk, resulting in improved SEO performance, traffic, and form submission rates by up to 1333%.

#### M.G.H DESIGN SERVICES (REMOTE)

Contract and project-based Visual and Experience Designer . 2014 - 2020

#### BH ENGINEERING OFFICE (BEIRUT, LEBANON)

Architect • Branding Designer • Procurement Officer • 2015 • 2019

#### BERNARD KHOURY / DW5 STUDIOS (BEIRUT, LEBANON)

Intern Architect Intern UI Designer 2013

#### ABAR ARQUITECTOS (BARCELONA, SPAIN)

Intern Architect . 2012